FARHAD NOORALAHZADEH

farhad.nooralahzadeh@uzh.ch

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/farhad-nooralahzadeh/

Summary

"I am a postdoctoral researcher at University of Zurich (UZH) with 9 years of experience in the field of Natural Language Processing and Machine Learning applications. I completed my Ph.D degree at the University of Oslo in the Language Technology group on *Low-Resource Adaptation of Neural NLP Models*. Currently, I am working at the Department of Computational linguistics and KrauthammerLab (UZH and USZ) on Multilingual Neural Machine Translation and Multi-Modal, Multilingual Medical Report Generation projects."

Education

• University of Oslo—Oslo-Norway,

May 2016- June 2020 PhD fellow in Language Technology group (SIRIUS Center) Low-Resource Adaptation of Neural NLP Models

• Université Lumière Lyon 2 — Lyon-France,

Sep 2011-July 2013

MSc in Data Mining and Knowledge Management (Erasmus Mundus programe)

- GPA:18.22 (M2) 15 (M1)

• IRAN University of Science and technology—Tehran-Iran

BSc in Industrial Engineering at System analysis and planning

Related Professional Experience

- Department of Computational Linguistics , University of Zurich—CL-UZH Postdoctoral Fellow: Nov 2021 present
- Krauthammer Lab, University of Zurich & University Hospital Zurich—UZH Research Assistant / Postdoctoral Fellow: Jun 2020 present
- Institut national de recherche en informatique et en automatique- Sophia Antipolis—INRIA

Research Engineer: Feb 2015-May 2016

• École Polytechnique de Montréal. Montreal—Canada Research Assistance: May 2014- Oct 2014

• XEROX Research Centre Europe. Grenoble- France—XRCE Research and Development Engineer: Oct 2013-April 2014

• XEROX Research Centre Europe. Grenoble - France—XRCE

Intern(1st prize for presentation of internship project): March 2013-Sep 2013

• Kayson Co. IRAN—KCC System Engineer and SAP Business One Admin: Dec 2008 - Jul 2011

Netsis Group, Inc—PNS
 ERP Implementation Project Manager: Apr 2006 - Nov 2008

System Specialist: Jun 2002 - March 2006

Publication

- Farhad Nooralahzadeh, Nicolas Perez Gonzalez, Thomas Frauenfelder, Koji Fujimoto, Michael Krauthammer: **Progressive Transformer-Based Generation of Radiology Reports.** Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: EMNLP, November 7–11, 2021
- Farhad Nooralahzadeh, Giannis Bekoulis, Johannes Bjerva and Isabelle Augenstein:
 Zero-Shot Cross-Lingual Transfer with Meta Learning. Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, EMNLP, November 16–20, 2020
- Farhad Nooralahzadeh, Jan Tore Lønning, Lilja Øvrelid: Reinforcement-based denoising
 of distantly supervised NER with partial annotation. Proceedings of the second
 Workshop in Deep LEARNING FOR LOW-RESOURCE NLP (DeepLo) 2019, EMNLP, Nov.
 3, Hong-Kong,
- Farhad Nooralahzadeh, Lilja Øvrelid: **SIRIUS-LTG: An Entity Linking Approach to Fact Extraction and Verification**. Proceedings of the First Workshop on Fact Extraction and VERification (FEVER) 2018, EMNLP, Nov. 1, Brussels, Belgium,
- Farhad Nooralahzadeh, Lilja Øvrelid: Syntactic Dependency Representations in Neural Relation Classification. Proceedings of the International Workshop on Relevance of Linguistic Structure in Neural Architectures for NLP, ACL 2018, July 15-20, Melbourne
- Farhad Nooralahzadeh, Lilja Øvrelid, Jan Tore Lønning: SIRIUS-LTG-UiO at SemEval-2018 Task 7: Convolution neural network with shortest dependency path for relation extraction and classification in scientific papers. Proceedings of the 12th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation (SemEval-2018)
- Farhad Nooralahzadeh, Lilja Øvrelid, Jan Tore Lønning: Evaluation of Domain-specific Word Embeddings using Knowledge Resources. Proceedings of the 11th International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2018), May 7-12, Miyazaki, Japan
- Farhad Nooralahzadeh, Cédric Lopez, Elena Cabrio, Fabien L. Gandon, Frédérique Segond: Adapting Semantic Spreading Activation to Entity Linking in Text. NLDB 2016: 74-90
- Cédric Lopez, Farhad Nooralahzadeh, Elena Cabrio, Frédérique Segond, Fabien Gandon: ProVoc: une ontologie pour décrire des produits sur le Web. IC 2016: 61-72
- Cédric Lopez, Matthieu Osmuk, Dana Popovici, Farhad Nooralahzadeh, Domoina Rabarijaona, Fabien Gandon, Elena Cabrio, Frédérique Segond: Du TALN au LOD: Extraction d'entités, liage, et visualisation. IC 2016: 231-234
- Farhad Nooralahzadeh, Caroline Brun and Claude Roux. **Part of Speech Tagging for French Social Media Data.** The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING 2014) Dublin, Ireland, August 23-29, 2014.
- Farhad Nooralahzadeh, Viswanathan Arunachalam, and Costin-Gabriel Chiru. 2012
 Presidential Elections on Twitter An Analysis of How the US and French Election were
 Reflected in Tweets. In Proceedings of the 2013, 19th International Conference on Control
 Systems and Computer Science (CSCS '13). IEEE Computer Society.

Program committee

NAACL: 2021EACL: 2021

• NoDaLiDa: 2021, 2020, 2019

• ACL: 2020

• EMNLP: 2021, 2020, 2019

• LREC: 2020

Skills

- DataBase: Microsoft SQL server, MySql,Postgresql
- Programing Language and Scripte: C++, Java, Python, javaScript
- IDE, Tools and Softwares: Pytorch, Tenserflow, Keras, SciPy, Numpy, Scikit-learn, pandas, Spacy, Stanford CoreNLP, NLTK, Gensim, R, Weka, SPARQL, Prolog, Crystal Report, React, React Native, NetBeans, LATEX, Git, Maven
- NLP related Deep Learning Techniques: RNN/LSTM, Attention, Transformer, BERT, GPT-2, BART
- Language (From native to intermediate level): Persian, Turkish, English, Spanish, French

References Available to Contact

• Lilja Øvrelid: professor , Language Technology Group , Department of Informatics, University of Oslo

Email:liljao@ifi.uio.no phone: +47-22840850

- **Isabelle Augenstein :** Associate Professor , Department of Computer Science , University of Copenhagen *Email:augenstein@di.ku.dk*
- **Jan Tore Lønning:** Professor , Language Technology Group , Department of Informatics, University of Oslo

Email:jtl@ifi.uio.no, phone : +47-22840120